Stanislav Pogorskii

Stanislav.pogorskii@gmail.com □ +995511107834 ■ https://www.linkedin.com/in/pogorskii/

### **SUMMARY**

Diligent Full Stack Developer with more than 2 years of experience working with HTML, CSS (+SASS, Tailwind), JavaScript, jQuery, TypeScript, React and NextJS. Always learning new technologies and improving existing skills. Passionate for creating modern, accessible and effective websites and web applications. Loves writing readable and easily-maintainable clean code.

#### **SKILLS**

Core stack: HTML, CSS (SASS, Tailwind), JavaScript, TypeScript.

Libraries/Frameworks: React, NextJS, Astro.

Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL.

Backend: NodeJS, Go.

Misc: Zod, Redux, Autho, D3js, Framer Motion.

Languages: Russian (native), English (C1), German (A1, currently learning).

### **PROJECTS**

### WIITCO (When Is It Coming Out)

https://wiitco.vercel.app/ | https://github.com/pogorskii/wiitco-app • November 2023 - Present

- · Created a modern NextJS/TypeScript SPA that solves a real-world problem.
- · Combined vastly different APIs into a cohesive and comfortable interface.
- · Set up PostgreSQL to store movies, tv shows and video games data.
- · Converted external games DB from error-prone noSQL to robust PostgreSQL.
- · Implemented additional Go backend to handle DB syncing.
- · Implemented Autho authentication.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Head Editor of Games and Movies

Sports.ru

January 2022 - Present

- · Lead a team of 10 authors.
- Established connections with 20+ publishers and gaming companies.
- · Increased Games and Movies views by 150%+.

### **Frontend Developer**

Freelance

February 2022 - November 2023

- · Created various websites and landings using clients' Figma files.
- · Made designs more accessible and consistent, improving contrast, typography and spacing.
- · Implemented interactivity, ranging from animations and carousels to cleaning cost calculators for users.

#### Author

Sports.ru

June 2019 - December 2021

- · 400+ articles about various topics, including video games, movies and IT.
- · A guest presenter at a live awards show.
- · Interviews with English-speaking developers without a translator.

# **EDUCATION**

## Lower post-secondary vocational education in Programming

Khimki College of Space Engineering · Moscow, Russia · 2017

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

## The Complete JavaScript Course 2023: From Zero to Expert!

Udemy • 2023

- · Learned all the core principles and patterns of modern JavaScript.
- · Build web apps using DOM manipulation before diving into React and other libraries/frameworks.